

# Aditya Raj

## Software Engineer

A dedicated and enthusiastic graduate with experience in developing enterprise applications using Spring Boot, Javascript, Kotlin and Javascript. Excellent interpersonal skills and the ability to communicate at all levels. I enjoy part of being in a successful team and thrive in diverse working conditions.

adityaraj5252@gmail.com

Berlin, Germany

S adityaraj52521

+4917687985062

adityaraj52.github.io

github.com/adityaraj52

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineer** MicroDoc GmbH

04/2019 - Present

Berlin, Germany

Tasks

- Active communication and participation in providing and implementing ideas for developing existing application framework
- Working in an agile team to provide APIs for web and mobile app development for Sparkasse bank. This involves extensive use of Java and Kotlin based front end development and providing APIs for several UI Components based on Spring Thymeleaf and Kotlin

# Java Software Engineer Accenture Technologies GmbH

04/2018 - 03/2019

Wolfsburg, Germany

Tasks

- Providing backend support for the JAVA Enterprise application
- Implementing possible improvements such as in-memory database, integrating algorithm to support custom printing abilities for web pages

# **Research Intern**Salzgitter Flachstahl GmbH

07/2017 - 06/2018

Salzgitter, Germany

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed a unique Voting Outliers Using Randomized Sampling (VOTERS) algorithm to analyse defect patterns in long steel bars. The algorithm was tested in R and was integrated to Salzgitter JAVA based software to support automated extraction of outliers from XML files using JAXB, dimensionality reduction and unsupervised machine learning.
- Improved steel quality classification system of the company using Unsupervised Machine Learning.

## **EDUCATION**

# Master of Internet Technologies and Information Systems

Technische Universität Clausthal

09/2015 - 03/2018

Clausthal-Zellerfeld, Germany, Grade: 1.4/5

### Courses

- Machine Learning
  - ng Database as a service
- Wireless Sensor Networks
- Simulation Sciences

### **SKILLS**



## **WORK PROJECTS**

Sparkasse Internet Banking Framework Development (08/2019 - Present)

 Upgraded internet banking desktop application with Spring Thymeleaf and dynamic data binding using Java and Kotlin

Sparkasse Mobile Application Framework (04/2018 - 07/2019)

 Improved testing framework for mobile application and integrated customised UI components specific to Sparkasse requirements

Volkswagen Dealer Portal Application Development (06/2018 - Present)

- Integrated feature requests and custom functionalities in VW dealer portal based on Struts, Java EE, Spring and Rest API
- Provided unique solution to generalise internationalised pdf generation

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Published a research paper on Cooperative Localityaware Data Processing in Heterogeneous Wireless Sensor Networks project at Fachgespr ach Fog Computing conference.

https://www.areinhardt.de/publications/2018/Raj\_FGFC\_2018.pdf

Received DAAD Scholarship to pursue Bachelors thesis at TU Clausthal, Germany in the field of cooperative autonomous vehicles using Agent based simulations

### **LANGUAGES**

German
Limited Working Proficiency

English

Full Professional Proficiency